--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 春天　字幕来源: iTunes　字幕调校: 春天
"河狸五金行"
欢迎光临
Welcome to the store.
您是勤奋的河狸吗
Are you a Busy Beaver?
不 我并不是
No, I am not a Busy Beaver.
"绳子"
您是常客吗
Are you a Frequent Beaver?
加入会员即可享用折扣
Join our rewards club for savings.
购买本店提供的优惠商品
You can get your teeth into our dam good deals.
别忘了
Don't forget:
需要协助请向店员咨询
If you need help, ask a Beaver.
哦
Oh.
我能为你效劳吗
Hey. Oh. Can I, uh, help you with that, sir?
你觉得我不会割绳子
Do you think I don't know how to cut rope?
没啦 只是通常都由店员服务
No, it's just we usually do that for ya.
你觉得我会割伤自己 然后告你们
Do you think I'm gonna cut myself and bleed all over your floor and sue you?
不是
No.
那我就不需要帮忙
Then I don't need your help.
祝你今天愉快
Have an excellent day.
我是忙碌的河狸
I'm a Busy Beaver.
白痴
Idiot.
您需要的东西都有找到吗
Did you, um, find everything you were lookin' for today?
是的
Yes.
太好了
Good.
让我看看
Let's see here.
总共3.47美元
Uh, your total is 3.47.
你收我6呎绳子的钱
You charged me for 6 feet of rope.
是的 1码是99美分
Oh, yes, it's 99¢ a yard.
我没拿2码 只拿了5呎
I didn't get 2 yards. I got 5 feet.
我们不是以呎计价 是以码计价
Yeah, we don't charge by the foot. We charge by the yard.
1码99美分是1呎33美分 乘以5是1.65美元
99¢ a yard is 33¢ a foot, times 5, that's 1.65.
你却收我1.98美元
You charged me $1.98.
你很会算术
You're good at math. Um...
我知道 但我不能照你说的 输入电脑
No, I know, but I can't put it into the computer the way that you just said.
哪种电脑不会简单的算术
What the hell kind of computer can't do simple math?
-我要找店长 -他在吃午餐
-Can I speak to your manager? -He's at lunch.
吃午餐 这年头大家只在乎吃吃吃
Lunch. All anyone cares about these days is lunch.
-现场有谁可以负责  -副店长
-Is there anyone else in charge? -You want the assistant manager?
-好的 请他来 -好喔
-Yes, I'd like the assistant manager. -'Kay.
嘿 泰勒
Hey, Taylor?
泰勒 请到收银台
Taylor? To the front register.
如何
What's up?
嘿 泰勒
Hey, Taylor.
这就是副店长 她几岁
This is the assistant manager? How old is she?
妳不是该去上体育课吗
Shouldn't you be in gym class?
抱歉 什么
Sorry, what?
拿去 我有零钱
Here. I got some change.
我替你付多出来的钱
Let me cover that extra 33¢ for you.
我不要你的钱 这跟钱无关
Sir, I do not want your 33¢. And this is not about 33¢.
事实是 我只要5呎长的绳子
This is about the fact that I got 5 feet of rope because I want 5 feet of rope.
不应该付6呎长绳子的钱
And I shouldn't have to pay for 6 feet of rope if I don't want 6 feet.
你要多拿1呎长的绳子吗
Did you want another foot of rope?
又来了
Not again.
这到底有多难
How hard can this be?
"不住在这里 就不要把垃圾丢这里"
脚踏车应该放在这里
That bike goes over here.
嘿 你在干嘛
Hey! What the hell?
那是我的
That's mine.
-应该停在单车架 -我只离开一下子
-It belongs in the bike rack. -I was only gone half a minute.
下次我会把它锁进失物招领室
Next time, I'll lock it up in the lost and found.
超难搞的老头子
Grumpy old bastard.
真是的
Jeez.
"住户停车许可证"
没挂在后照镜上面
Not on the mirror.
嘿 奥托
-Hey, Otto!
好了
Okay.
嘿
Hey!
"戴恩美利卡建设公司"
再让那丑八怪尿在我门口看看
Don't you dare let that little rat dog piss on my walkway again.
-我知道是妳 -别理他 王子
-I know it was you. -Ignore him, Prince.
他是个超难搞老头子 不知道是谁尿的
He's a nasty, bitter old man. And he has no idea who's doing that.
妳家的绝对有尿
Well, it was one of you.
叫妳那废柴男友别在大庭广众扭腰献宝
And tell that useless boyfriend of yours to stop stretching his groin in public.
又不是14岁的体操选手
Looks like a 14-year-old Romanian gymnast, for God's sakes.
快点 快滚开
Go on. Get outta here.
快滚开
Go.
"工程部门"
大人物来了
There he is, the big man himself.
这是在搞什么
What's all this?
退休蛋糕 庆祝你退休
It's, well, retirement cake, I guess. Call it what you like.
"玩得开心"
"Have fun."
玩得开心
玩什么
Doing what?
下半辈子玩得开心啊 我们想…
Have fun with the rest of your life. We wanted to, you know...
庆祝
Celebrate?
对啊 不
Yes! Well, no.
只是欢送你
Give you a nice send-off.
欢送
"Nice."
别这样 奥托
Come on, Otto.
是你自己决定要走
You're the one who decided to leave.
你也拿到不少资遣费
And you did get a nice severance package.
你把我从营运部调走
You took me off Operations.
削减我的工时
You cut back on my hours.
把我训练的泰瑞升为我主管
You made Terry, who I trained, my supervisor.
泰瑞没有手机就不知道何年何月
Terry, who can barely figure out what year it is without his phone.
所以我是拿了资遣费
So, yes, I took the severance package.
很遗憾你这么想
I'm sorry you see it that way.
并购之后大家都得调适
We all had to adjust after the merger.
但你这些年来对公司贡献良多
But you've been quite an asset to this company over the years, so--
是真的 你非常可靠
You have. Reliable as hell.
我们会怀念你订的进度表
We're gonna miss those schedules of yours.
敬奥托
To Otto!
-敬奥托
-To Otto! -To Otto.
奥托 要吃一块你的脸吗
Okay, Otto. Want a piece of your face?
谁饿了
-Who's hungry?
"此路不通 无证禁止停车"
看看啊
Look at this.
不行
No, no.
嘿 等等
Hey, hey, wait!
不不不 妳不可以没有许可就开进来
No, no, no. Hey, you cannot use this road without a permit.
我没停车 只是运送包裹
I'm not parking. I just dropped off a package.
招牌又没说可以运送包裹
The sign doesn't say anything about packages, does it?
只说需要许可 妳没有许可
It says "permits" and you don't have one.
这条街是条死巷
This is not a through street.
祝您愉快 先生
Have a nice day, sir.
妳每次开进来
Every time you come in here
就代表有个住户不能停车
that means one of the residents can't park in front of their homes!
别人不会这样 开白卡车的都很乖
The other guys don't do this. The guys with the white trucks.
怎么你们棕色的都来乱
How come it's always you brown guys?
我说的不是妳的肤色
And I don't mean that racially!
喂
Hello.
-抱歉 你听得到吗
Oh, hi. Sorry, can you hear me?
-是的
Yes.
-我是苏珊
It's Susan.
-哪位是苏珊
Susan who?
我有关于健保的好消息
I have great news about your health insurance.
不不不 机器人
Oh, no, no, no. Robot, robot, robot!
我要找谁才能停用这支电话
Well, who do I have to talk to to get this phone number disconnected?
用户服务部门
That's Account Services.
能帮我转接或是要按个号码
Can you transfer me or should I press a number?
我听那段音乐七分钟了
Well, I have been listening to that music for seven minutes.
很抱歉 安德森先生
I do apologise, Mr Anderson.
我想停止我家的供电
I would like the electricity shut off at this residence.
-您要搬家  -不 我要取消帐户
-Are you moving home? -No, I am cancelling the account.
A-N-D-E-R-S-O-N.
A-N-D-E-R-S-O-N
这六天为何不能退费
And why can't you refund me for the six days?
O-T-T-O.
O-T-T-O
是公司规定
Oh, it's policy.
我的规定是多付六天瓦斯费
Well, my policy is that if I'm going to pay for six days of gas,
就能多用六天的瓦斯
then I will use six days of gas.
就这样
Then we are done here.
白痴
Idiots.
好了
Okay.
往前 停下来 往前
Go, go, go. Stop. Go.
好了 停下来
Okay. Yeah. Stop.
倒车 你看不到 小心点 用原力
Back. You're in the blind spot, be careful. Use the Force.
-噢 不行 -你会开上人行道
Good, good. No, you're going on the sidewalk.
很好
Okay.
倒车倒车
Back, back, back.
另一边
Go away.
停下来
-Stop. Stop.
可恶
Ah, shit.
他在搞什么鬼
What the hell is he doing?
没错 我也是这么说
Yes! Exactly! That's exactly what I was saying.
你们不能随便开进来
-Hey, you can't just drive here.
我没开车 我在开车吗
I'm not driving. Am I driving the car? No.
没有许可证不能开车进来
You can't just bring a car on this street without a permit.
我们有停车许可证 这里 瞧
No, we have a parking permit. Right here. See?
你放在口袋干嘛
What the hell's it doing in your pocket?!
我是驾驶啊
Well, I'm the driver.
我们在这里租屋
We're renting here. Yeah.
206号
In 206.
那也不代表 你可以把拖车停在门口
That doesn't mean you can back the trailer up to your front door.
其实我只是想路边停车
No, I wasn't. I was, uh, parallel parking.
哪个路边
Parallel to what?
我停得不是很好 对吧
Yeah, that, uh, didn't go so well, huh?
我会再试一次
I'll just give it another try.
我的天啊
-Oh, my God.
好吧
Okay.
很好
Good. Good!
继续倒车
Keep backing away. Keep backing away.
再退后一点
Now go away more.
好了 我行的
Okay, I got this.
-先往另一边 -小心点
The other way, but first the other way.
这就对了
-Easy. -Exactamente.
-小心点 -很好
-Easy, easy. -Uh-huh. Good.
不不不 不对
No. No, no. What? No!
不不不 停下来
-No, no, no! Stop! Stop, stop, stop! Stop!
停下来 下车
-Stop! Stop. Get outta the car.
-下车 -对不起
-Get outta the car. -I'm sorry.
你不会倒车
How you could make it this far through life
怎么能活到现在
without knowing how to back up a trailer.
就连只有一只脚的狗狗 都能停得比你好
My God, a dog with one front paw and cataracts coulda done better than that.
而且是自排车 给我钥匙
And an automatic, of course. Give me the keys.
钥匙在瓶架里
Oh, they're in the cupholder.
要用按键启动
It's a push-button start.
我知道
No, I knew that.
那是什么
What the hell is that?
那是雷达
Uh, that's the radar.
拖车太靠近汽车了
The trailer's too close to the side of the car.
所以才会哔哔叫
That's why it's still beeping, but--
好吧
Okay.
你好
Hello.
妳好
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
奥托
-Otto. -Otto?
奥托 O-T-T-O
Otto. O-T-T-O.
我是艾比 O-T-T-O
I'm Abbie, O-T-T-O.
我是露娜
And I'm Luna.
幸会了
Nice to meet you.
他挺厉害的
Oh, that was good, huh?
只试一次就搞定
He just did it in one shot, huh?
-太好了 -谢谢你 先生
-Perfecto! -Thank you, sir.
需要靠雷达才会倒车的人
Anyone who thinks they need to use radar to back up a car
不应该开车
shouldn't be allowed to drive one.
也不应该用收音机
They shouldn't be allowed to use the radio.
我也这么说
That's what I said.
许可证要挂在后照镜 不是放在口袋
And the permit goes on the rear-view mirror. Not in your pocket!
-好啦 -了解
-Okay, okay. -Got it.
-再见 谢谢你 -谢谢 你真好心
-Bye! Thank you! -Thank you, sir. That was very nice.
白痴
Idiot.
都准备好了吗
You guys all ready?
好了
Okay.
很好
All right.
东西要拿好
Bring your stuff, okay?
来吧 亲爱的
Come on, sweeties.
乖女儿 东西要拿好
Chiquitita, take your stuff.
"大师与玛格丽特"
还有几个空书架
How much more shelf space is left?
三个
Three shelves.
-妳有几箱书  -七 八箱
-How many more boxes of books do you have? -Seven or eight.
我再替妳做一个书架
"Then I'll build you another bookcase."
Then I'll build you another bookcase.
-嗨 -嘿
-Hi. -Hey.
嗨 欧托
Hi. Otto.
对吧
Right? Yes?
是奥托
Otto.
我就是这么说的 不是吗
Yeah, that's what I said. No? What did I say--?
那不重要 是奥托 O-T-T-O
It doesn't matter what you said. Otto. O-T-T-O.
-欧托 -奥托
-Ah! Otto. -Otto.
哦 欧托 正反的拼法都一样
Otto. Okay, so it's the same forward that is backwards.
-奥托 -是奥托 玛丽
-Otto. -It's Otto, Mari.
这名字很少听到
It's just you don't hear that name very often.
我就常听到
I do.
好吧 要是你在忙 我们再回来
Okay. If we're interrupting, we can always come back.
你们想要什么
What is it you want?
我带了点吃的
I brought you some food.
为什么
Why?
你看起来很饿
Because you looked hungry.
所以我们才会这么速配
That's why we go so well together.
她喜欢下厨 我喜欢吃
She loves to cook, and I like to eat everything.
反正呢 我们只想…
Anyway, we just, uh...
我们想正式自我介绍
We wanted to properly introduce ourselves
因为我们会是邻居 所以…
because we're gonna be neighbours and everything, so...
-所以…
-So... -Okay.
-好吧 再见
-Okay. -Bye.
我的名字是玛丽索
My name is Marisol.
我是汤米
And I'm Tommy.
奥托
Otto.
你总是这么难搞吗
Are you always this unfriendly?
我才没有难搞
I'm not unfriendly.
-你有一点难搞 -并没有
-I'd say you're a little unfriendly. -I'm not unfriendly.
-有一点 -并没有
-Un poquito. -I am not.
没有 好 你不难搞
No? Okay, you're not.
没啦 你一点都不难搞
No, no, no, no. You're not unfriendly.
你每字每句都热情如火
Every word you say is like a warm cuddle.
是真的
It really is.
好好享用
Enjoy it.
这是什么
What is it?
别弄翻莎莎酱
Be careful with the salsa, please.
那是巧克力酱炖鸡
It's, um, pollo con mole.
很好吃喔
It's really good.
那是墨西哥菜
It's a Mexican dish.
我是墨西哥人
I'm Mexican.
我在萨尔瓦多出生 我爸是那里人
I was born in El Salvador because my father is from there.
但我妈是墨西哥人 所以先去墨西哥…
But my mom is Mexican, so we went to first Mexico and then--
你呢 我是IT顾问
-And you? -I'm an IT consultant.
我来自加州安那翰
Oh, I'm from Anaheim.
-你来自安那翰
Oh, from Anaheim.
-没错
Anaheim, yeah.
我其实来自艾尔帕索
Yeah. El Paso.
我有事要做
Okay, well, I have some things I need to do.
不好意思 奥托先生
Excuse me, Mr Otto.
我能向你借楼赖把吗
You wouldn't have an Alvin wrench I could borrow, would you?
你是说罗赖把吧
You mean an Allen wrench.
不 是楼赖把
No, an Alvin wrench.
-是罗赖把 -罗赖把
-It's Allen wrench. -Allen wrench.
罗赖把 对吧 是罗赖把
It's "Allen" wrench, right? It's Allen wrench.
是楼赖把
It's Alvin.
他一直在说楼赖把
All morning, "Alvin wrench, Alvin wrench."
是楼赖把 相信我
Honey, it's Alvin, trust me.
我朋友都说是楼赖把
Everybody else I know calls it an Alvin wrench.
你朋友都说错了
-Everybody else you know is wrong. -Oh, yeah? You wanna Google it?
-妳要上网查吗  -天啊
My God.
Google it! Google it!
上网查维基百料
Google it. Wikipediale. Wikipediale.
手机给我
Give me your phone.
才不要 用你的手机
No, my phone. You use your phone.
你要什么尺寸
Do you know what size you need?
一般的尺寸就行
Ah, just the usual size.
整组都拿去
Take the set.
-谢谢
-Thank you.
你有事要做 我们先走了
We go because you have things to do, so...
你又想要什么
What do you want, huh?
她很美吧 儿子
Isn't she beautiful, son?
那就是雪佛兰的引擎
That's a Chevy engine for you.
可靠耐用
Dependable.
这世上可靠的东西并不多
Not enough you can depend on in this world.
爸 这是奥托
Dad, this is Otto.
那就够了 亲爱的
That's enough now, darling.
"鲜花 两束$8"
两束8美元
Huh.Two for $8?
也许我应该开车撞死自己 那会有用
Maybe I should just run myself over with a car. That'll work.
找到妳喜欢的鲜花
Found some of the flowers you like.
粉红色的
Pink.
而且有打折
There was a deal on 'em.
优惠价 两束8美元
On sale. Two for 8 bucks.
抱歉没能早点带来
I'm sorry I didn't get 'em here earlier.
我被耽搁了
Got distracted.
认识了新邻居
By some new neighbours.
她老公是笨蛋
Nitwit husband.
连罗赖把都不知道
Didn't even know an Allen wrench from one of the Chipmunks.
当然是租客
Renters, of course.
不用给出承诺
No commitment to anything.
"索妮娅"
我知道 也许他们还买不起房子
I know, I know. Maybe they can't afford to buy yet.
但是如果可恶的建商
But what will they do when those real estate bastards
决定拆掉他们的房子
decide to tear down their house
改建廉价公寓该怎么办
and put up more of those ricky-ticky condos, huh?
我保证一定会发生
It's gonna happen. I promise you.
他们已经在铁门附近
They're already driving around the gates,
乱开车还开上草地
driving right across the grass.
戴恩美利卡
Dye & Merika.
哪个白痴建商会取这种名字
What idiot thought that was a good name for a real estate company?
听起来像是"垂死的美国"
Sounds like "dying America."
那倒是真的
It is, of course.
连像样的挂钩都买不到了
Can't even buy a decent screw hook anymore.
绳子也不用英呎计价
Or rope by the foot.
没有妳什么都不对
Nothing works when you're not home.
下一个
Next.
我怀疑你有肥厚性心肌症
I suspect you have hypertrophic cardiomyopathy,
那是遗传的心肌…
which is a genetic enlargement of the--
我知道
I know.
我爸也有
My father had it.
你应该能活很久
Well, you'll likely be around a good long time,
但恐怕没办法当兵
but I'm afraid your military prospects end here.
下一个
Next.
一张匹兹堡回程车票
One return ticket to Pittsburgh, please.
1.10美元
That'll be 1.10.
谢谢妳
Thank you.
借过
Coming through.
嘿 妳的书掉了
Hey, you dropped your book!
小姐 妳的书掉了
Miss, you dropped your book! Hey!
那是我的书吗
Is that mine?
什么
What?
是的 我看到妳掉了 所以就…
-Yes. I saw you dropped it, so I...
"大师与玛格丽特"
真是感谢你
Thank you so much.
我看到一半 很想知道结局
I'm halfway through reading it. I would hate not knowing how it ends.
来吧 坐下来
Oh, here. Why don't you join me?
我是索妮娅
I'm Sonya.
我是奥托
I'm Otto.
那是我爸的名字
It was my father's name.
我正要去看我爸
I'm on my way to visit my father right now.
每周四都会去
I go every Thursday.
你常搭这班火车吗
Do you take this train a lot?
没有 我只是来做兵役体检
Oh, no, I had to come into town for my Army physical.
天啊
Oh, God.
不知道会遇上什么一定很难熬
Oh, that must be so hard, not knowing what you're gonna face over there.
你何时会离开
我没有…
-When are you leaving? -I'm not--
还有一阵子
Not for a while.
验票
Tickets, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢妳
All right, thank you.
你搭错火车了 这是东向车票
I'm afraid you're on the wrong train. This is an eastbound ticket.
我一定是…
I must have, um...
我下一站就下车
I'll get off at the next station.
要补多少钱
Uh, how much is it?
1.75美元
Uh, $1.75.
1元
One.
拿去 我有零钱
Here. I have some change.
谢谢妳
Thank you.
拿去 谢谢 祝你愉快
There you go. Thank you. Have a good day.
还有两毛五
A quarter to spare.
1964年的硬币
It's 1964.
纯银的
-It's pure silver. -Oh?
留着吧 那代表好运
Keep it, then. It's lucky.
的确是
Yes, it is.
"谢谢 食物很有意思"
奥托 清晨巡逻有点晚吧
Hey, Otto! A little late for your morning rounds, isn't it?
不会
No.
不会 你不是该去上班吗
No? Aren't you supposed to be at work?
不用
No.
酷喔 要过来吃午饭吗
Oh. Cool. You wanna come over for lunch, then?
午饭
-Lunch.
对啊
Yeah.
不 不
No, no.
有兴趣的话今天吃猪里肌肉
Well, it's pork tenderloin, in case you change your mind!
不不不
No, no, no, no.
嘿 不好意思
Hey, excuse me.
就是你
It was you.
这是私人道路 铁门是用来减少车流
This is a private road, and these gates are to keep down the flow of traffic.
不是让白痴驾驶把车开上草地
Not so idiot drivers can go around them and tear up the grass.
被你逮到了 我是建商员工
-Okay. You got me. I'm with Dye & Merika.
我会请管理员来帮你修好
I'm gonna have the groundskeeper come down and fix that up for ya, okay?
比新的更好 祝你愉快
Good as new. Even better. You have a good one now, okay?
规定就是规定
The rules are here for a reason.
我知道你们想干嘛
I know what you guys are up to.
好吧 安德森先生 你说了算
Okay, Mr Anderson. Whatever you say.
继续守望相助
Keep up the neighbourhood watch.
快出来 你这小家伙
-Get out here, you little bugger!
出来啊
Come on. Yeah.
快给我出来
Get out here!
妳敢再丢一块石头 我就会
You throw one more rock,
把妳的臭狗踢到屋顶
and I swear I'll dropkick that little rat dog of yours right over the roof.
我不是向你家丢石头 那只猫抓伤王子
No, I'm not throwing it at your house. That nasty cat scratched Prince.
我要杀了那只臭猫
I'm gonna kill that piece of shit.
想都别想
No, you're not.
关你什么事 那是只野猫
What do you care? It's feral.
全身上下可能都是病
It's probably full of all sorts of disgusting diseases.
妳也一样 但我不会向妳丢石头
So are you, most likely. I don't throw rocks at you.
安迪
Andy.
-怎么了 -你听到他这次骂我什么吗
-What's up? -Did you hear what he just said this time?
我跟你说过他常骂我
I told you before about how he talks to me.
赶快逃吧
Get outta here while you can.
我不是你的朋友
I'm not your friend.
建商说要把老人家都送到安养院
Dye & Merika said they'll get all the old people on this street into a home.
越快越好
The sooner the better!
你好 又怎么了
-Hello. -What now?
我只想把扳手还给你
I just wanted to bring the wrenches back.
我找到家具附上的扳手 恭喜了
-I found one that came with the furniture. -Congratulations.
我为你做了沙波洛
And I made you some salpores de arroz.
巧克力酱炖鸡
Is that chicken and mole?
不是 这是萨尔瓦多饼干 我爸的最爱
No. These are Salvadoran cookies. They were my father's favourite, so...
很好吃喔 你一定会超爱
They're delicious. You're gonna love 'em.
对啊 因为是我做的
Yes, because I made them.
另外我也想向你借梯子
Also, Otto, I was wondering if you have a ladder I can borrow.
我们的窗户卡住了
Our window is jammed.
你为什么需要梯子
Why do you need a ladder?
是上面的窗户
Well, it's the one up there.
打不开
It won't open.
你想试着从外面打开
And you're gonna try to open it from the outside?
对 没错
Yeah. Right.
我去穿大衣
I'll get my coat.
好 谢谢你
Okay. Thank you.
我喜欢他挥手的样子
I like how his hands are waving.
把手插上去
Let's put the arm in.
-太好了 -安妮塔
-Good. -Anita.
奥托 打扰一下 我们的暖气坏了
Uh, Otto, hate to bother you, but, um, we don't have any heat.
能不能来看看
Could you come take a look?
试试替散热器排水
Try bleeding your radiators.
我该怎么做
How would I go about that?
替散热器排水
By bleeding the radiators.
奥托 别这么难搞
Otto. Don't be rude.
我没有难搞
I wasn't being rude.
有时候很难看得出来
Well, it's hard to tell the difference sometimes with Otto.
是啊
Yeah.
对了 我们才刚搬进206号
By the way, we, uh, just moved to 206.
-我是玛丽索 -我是汤米
-I'm Marisol. -I'm Tommy.
-欢迎 -幸会了
-Welcome, honey. -Nice meeting you.
我是安妮塔
I'm Anita.
我老公鲁本以前负责处理暖气
My husband, Reuben, is the one who used to handle the heat.
但我们知道总有一天
-Okay. -But we always knew a day would come
他会没办法处理这些事情
when he wouldn't be able to handle things around the house any longer.
鲁本把我踢出管委会时应该先想到
Maybe Reuben should have thought of that when he organised his coup.
那是很久以前的事
That was a long time ago.
踢出管委会
A coup?
那是个误会
It was a misunderstanding.
他把我踢出去
It was a coup.
奥托 快去帮安妮塔替散热器排气
Otto, can't you just go breathe Anita's radiators for her?
不 不能替散热器排气
No. Because you don't breathe radiators.
要替散热器排水
You bleed them.
-看看这块坡道 -那是索妮娅的
-Honey, look at this ramp. -That's Sonya's.
-拉拖车时就需要 -放下来
-This is what we needed for the trailer. -Put that down.
放下来 谁说你能碰它
Put that down! Who said you could touch that?!
-对不起 -你们全都给我滚
-Sorry. -All of you get outta here. Go, go.
拿了梯子就滚 全都给我滚
Take your ladder and go. Get outta here. All of you.
-好啦 -谢谢你
-Okay. -Thank you.
-谢谢你 -小心
Watch out.
好了
-Right. Right.
-谢谢你
-Thank you! -Thank you!
不行 你在这里干嘛
No. What are you doing in here?
你怎么会躲到里面
How did you get in here? Come on.
快滚 给我出去
Come on. Go! Get outta there.
出去 出去
No, get out. Get out of there.
快滚啊
Come on, go.
嘿
-Hey.
放开
Let go!
-Let go.
你敢抓伤我 我就咬你
You scratch me, I'll bite you.
学会教训了吧
-That'll teach you.
蠢猫
Stupid cat.
-嗨 奥托
-Hi, Otto!
奥 噢 托
O-T-T-O
奥托
Otto. Um...
我去年八月借水管给妳
I loaned you my garden hose last August.
只要还给我 我就帮妳替暖气排水
If you give it back to me, I'll bleed your radiators for you.
进来吧
Come in.
你的新邻居看起来人很好 对吧
So those new neighbours of yours, they seem quite lovely, don't you think?
好到不行
Lovely.
你可能很快就会有更多邻居了
Yeah, well, you may have some more new neighbours soon enough.
建商的人告诉我们…
The realty people, they've been telling us...
我和鲁本必须搬走
Reuben and I have to move out.
那全是屁话
No, that's a load of crap.
这房子是你们的
They don't own this house. You do.
我也是这么说
Yeah, well, that's what I said.
他们找上我们的儿子克里斯
They, uh, have been talking to our boy, Chris.
他说我照顾不了鲁本
Now he's saying that I can no longer take care of Reuben,
必须把他送去护理之家
that he needs to be in a special care place.
我也应该搬去安养院
And I should move into a retirement home.
克里斯懂什么 他是个白痴
What does Chris know about it? He's an idiot. He always has been.
他们不能逼妳做任何事
They can't make you do anything.
他知道我们在这里吗
Does he even know we're here?
当然知道
Of course he does.
别被他骗了
Don't let him fool you.
他头脑很清楚
He's still in there.
我去拿你的水管
Let me go find your hose.
这整个社区就快完蛋了
The whole neighbourhood is falling apart these days.
就连管委会都没有了
They don't even have a homeowners' association anymore.
没有人管理社区的事
No one left to keep things running.
不像我们以前那样
Not like we did.
我得把话说清楚
Now, just to be clear...
我还没原谅你
I still haven't forgiven you.
我只是没想到你病得这么快
I just didn't realise you would fall to shit so quickly.
现在…
Now...
他们要毁了我们努力建立的家园
they're tearing apart everything we worked so hard to build.
我都还没走 他们就想把我们赶走
I haven't even left yet, and they're trying to erase us.
我不会留下来看到那种事发生
Well, I am not staying around to see that happen.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
-永远离开 -午饭准备好了吗
-For good. -You ready for lunch?
-我做了你爱吃的奶油玉米
I'm making that creamed corn you like.
-谢谢妳
Oh, thank you.
谢谢你 奥托 抱歉拖了这么久
Thank you, Otto. I'm sorry it took so long to give it back.
一起吃午饭
Um, you wanna stay for lunch?
安妮塔做了猪里肌肉
Yeah, Anita made a pork tenderloin.
不了 我有很多事要做
No, I have a lot of things I have to do.
鲁本 你在干嘛
Reuben, what are you doing, hon?
-放手 -你在干嘛
-Let go. -What are you doing?
-放手 -鲁本
-Let go. -Reuben. Reuben.
放…你在干嘛
-Let... -What are you doing?
…手
...go.
天啊
Oh, man.
试试从里头打开
Try opening it from the inside a little.
比我想像的更高
It's higher than I thought.
我有点头晕
I'm a little bit dizzy, honey.
♪ Sun through the shadows ♪
♪ Light through the door ♪
♪ Your voice like an echo ♪
♪ That I can't hear anymore ♪
♪ So I follow your steps ♪
♪ While the love that you left ♪
♪ Is burned in my heart ♪
♪ With dreams in my mind ♪
♪ Of the next time that I ♪
♪ Have you in my arms ♪
♪ 'Cause I will tell you ♪
♪ The whole truth ♪
♪ That there's no colour ♪
♪ In the world without you ♪
看来我们都得搭下一班火车
Looks like we'll both have to take the next one.
奥托
Otto.
那是你爸的名字
It was your father's name.
妳还记得
You remembered.
你得回去军营吗
Did you have to go back to the military centre?
不 我想把车票钱还给妳
No, I wanted to pay you back for the train ticket.
请我吃晚饭不是更好吗
Wouldn't it be nicer if you invited me to dinner?
♪ The best gift of this life ♪
♪ Is to see you up close ♪
♪ And now and again... ♪
要进去吗
Shall we?
好啊 进去吧
Yeah, let's go in.
妳…
You're...
迟到了15分钟
...fifteen minutes late.
是吗
Am I?
♪ So I write it all down ♪
♪ All these moments I've found ♪
♪ Til I see you, my love ♪
你对什么有兴趣
So, what kinds of things interest you?
怎么说
Interest me like...?
你对什么有热情
What are you passionate about?
机器 引擎
Machines. Engines.
我想知道东西怎么运作
I like knowing how things work.
零件怎么运作来驱动车子
What each part does to make a car run smoothly.
那比一般人想得更复杂
It's more complicated than people realise.
化油器得先混和汽油和空气
A carburettor has to mix gas and air in just the right combination,
然后火星塞才能点火
and then the spark plug has to ignite that mixture,
驱动引擎活塞
which drives the piston
和传动轴…
and the connecting rods and the drive shaft--
你怎么知道这么多关于车子的事
Where did you learn so much about cars?
我爸教的
From my father.
我们只会聊车子 他是个好爸爸
It's all we really talked about. He was a good dad.
非常可靠
Dependable.
他去世了
He passed away.
两个月前
Two months ago.
非常突然
It was sudden.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
你妈呢
And your mom?
我不太记得她
Don't remember her much.
只记得她离开时的感觉
Just how it felt when she was gone.
你为什么没点主餐
Why didn't you get an entrée?
我在家吃过了
I ate at home.
为什么
Why?
好让妳想点什么就点什么
So you could order whatever you wanted.
听着 我骗了妳
Look, I lied to you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我体检没过 没能入伍
I'm not in the Army. I couldn't pass my physical.
我本来指望入伍就会有工作 但是…
If I had, at least I'd have a job now, which is what I was counting on.
并没有
But I don't.
我不知道我要做什么
And I don't know what I'm gonna do.
我该走了
I should go.
奥托
Otto!
我来了
I'm coming.
I'm coming!
干嘛 妳又要什么
What? What do you want?
-你在这里干嘛  -妳又在干嘛
-What are you doing here? -What are you doing?
-我在找你 -妳找到我了
-I'm looking for you. -Well, you found me.
你能不能带我去医院
Can you please take me to the hospital? Please?
汤米跌下梯子 刚刚被救护车接走
Tommy fell off the ladder, and the ambulance just took him away.
妳可以自己开那辆小小的进口车
Well, you can drive yourself in that imported toaster you call a car.
我没有驾照
I don't have a licence.
-妳几岁了  -30岁
-How old are you? -Huh? Thirty.
妳没有驾照
And you don't have a driver's licence?
我有驾车学习许可证
I have a driving's permit.
只是一直没学会其他的
I just never got to the other parts.
到底有多少其他的
How many other parts are there?
拜托了
Please!
专心点 拜托听我说
Focus! Please, listen!
汤米在医院 可能就快死了
Tommy is in the hospital, and he may be dying as we speak.
你要载我去医院或是逼我搭公车
So are you gonna drive me to the hospital, or are you gonna make me take a bus?
-我载妳去医院 -谢谢你
-I will drive you to the hospital. -Thank you.
有那么难吗
Was it so hard?
妳要去哪儿
Where are you going?
去带小孩子啊
I'm going to get the children!
小孩子
The children?
"杜肯医院"
把我擡起来
Pick me up, pick me up!
快打啊 不
Bam everywhere. No! No!
用力撞啊
Smack, smack, smack!
这些玩偶
These dolls.
他们是超级英雄吗
Are they some kind of superheroes?
他们是摔角手
Um, Luchador are wrestlers. Yeah.
-摔角手 -我找到熊先生的童书
Wrestlers.
我看到了
-I found a Mr Bear book! -So I see.
她要你念给她听
She wants you to read to her.
没错
Exactly.
你在吗 熊宝宝
"Are You There, Baby Bear?
你在吗 熊宝宝 熊先生问
'Are you there, Baby Bear?' Mr Bear says.
我的熊宝宝在哪里
'Where, oh where, is my Baby Bear.'"
不是啦 你要学熊讲话
No, talk like a bear.
熊不会讲话
Bears don't talk.
这只熊会
Um, this one does.
我的熊宝宝在哪里
"'Where, oh where, is my Baby Bear?'
熊宝宝 你是不是在树上
'Are you there, Baby Bear, up in that tree?'"
不是 那是一只猫头鹰
-No, it's an owl!
这里没有别人 只有宝宝和我
"'There's nobody here but baby and me.'
熊宝宝 你在地底下吗
'Are you there, Baby Bear, deep underground?'"
我不是熊宝宝
I'm no Baby Bear.
我是贝波
I'm Beppo!
嗨 贝波
-Hi, Beppo!
-想要看我变魔术吗  -想
-Do you want to see a trick? -Yes!
我正在念故事给她们听
Actually, I was reading to them.
我正在念故事给她们听 熊先生说
"Actually, I was reading to them," Mr Bear grumbled.
熊先生 可以借我个硬币吗
Say, could I borrow a coin, Mr Bear?
好啦 拜托
Yes, yes, yes, please?
拜托了
Please, please, please?
好啦 好啦
-Yes, yes, yes!
你要还给我
I need this back.
没问题
Absolutely.
小丑装不是他的 是医院的
He doesn't even own the costume. That's owned by the hospital.
他得赔钱给医院
He's gonna have to pay for that.
贝波带来欢乐 他自愿当志工
Beppo means happiness. He volunteers his time to be here.
奥托 你做了什么
Otto. What the hell did you do?
没什么
Nothing.
奥托阿公打了小丑
Abuelo Otto hit the clown.
我没有 明明就有
-I did not. -Yeah, you did.
摔角手阿公
Abuelo Luchadoro!
摔角手
Luchadoro!
全都是那小丑的错
It was all the clown's fault.
跑去哪儿了呀
Where is it going?
拿去
Here you go.
吹一下
Blow.
哇 在这里耶
Wow! Here it is!
你怎么做到的 这是魔术
-How'd you do that? -Oh, it's magic.
谢谢妳们
-Thank you.
希望妳们有个魔幻的一天
I hope you have a magical day!
-掰 -掰 贝波
-Bye! -Bye, Beppo!
谢谢妳们 等一下
-Thank you. -Hang on.
这不是我的硬币
This isn't my quarter.
从你耳朵出来的 是你的问题
Well, it came from your ear, sir, so that's a you problem.
这不是我的硬币
No, this isn't my quarter.
不不不 这不是你的硬币
"No, no, no. This is not your quarter."
听好 我给你个硬币 我说你一定要还给我
Look. I gave you a quarter that I said I needed back.
-你要一块钱  -你偷偷换掉
-You want a dollar? -And you switched them on me.
-瞒天过海 -你给我这个硬币
-The ol' switcheroo. -You gave me this quarter.
奥托会有麻烦吗?
Is Otto going to get in trouble?
-只是个硬币 -并不是
-It's just a quarter. -No, it's not.
-这是铜的 -拜托不要报警
-Do you see the copper? -He's not calling the coppers.
我给你一个1964年硬币 还给我
-I gave you a 1964 quarter. -Please calm down.
冷静一下
I want it back! Where is it?
-在哪里 快还给我  -警察先生帮帮我
-You have it on you. -Officer, help me.
-请求支援 小丑惹祸
129. We have a clown situation.
-东西在哪
Where is it?
放开那个小丑 先生 先生
Let go of the clown! Sir! Sir!
哈 1964年
A-ha! 1964.
我的玩具呢
Where's my toy?
在妳的背包里
It's in your backpack.
哪个口袋 有一百万个口袋
What pocket? There's a million pockets.
什么
What?
我爸以前也会这么笑
My father used to smile like that.
我没在笑
I'm not smiling.
没错
Exactly.
你不应该对小丑发脾气
You should never be mean to a clown.
-妳老公不来吗  -看啊
-What about Alvin Wrench, is he coming? -Look!
-大伙儿 -妈 他在那儿
-Hey, guys! -Mom, there he is!
麻烦把车开去接他
Pull the car up please, so we pick him up.
奥托
Otto!
-多谢了 -掰 摔角手阿公
-Thanks for driving us. -Bye, Abuelo Luchadoro.
-谢谢你 奥托 -晚安
-Thank you, Otto. -Okay, good night.
-掰 -再次多谢了
-Bye! -Thanks again, Otto.
掰了
Bye, then.
来吧 小姑娘
All right, ladies.
-走吧 -来吧
Let's go.
看看你的新腿 好像机器人喔
Look at your new leg! They look like a robot leg.
奥托
Otto!
天啊 牠死了吗
Oh, my God, is he dead?
没啦 牠大概在睡觉
No, he's probably sleeping.
奥托 别走 拜托把牠抱出来
Otto. No, no, no, please. Please. Please. Take him out. Please.
不要 妳怎么不抱
No, why can't you?
我怀孕了 不能碰猫 牠身上有虫
Because I'm pregnant. I cannot handle the cats because I can get the toxo thing.
牠自己跑进去 也能自己出来
Well, he got himself in there. He can get himself out of there.
你为什么这么难搞
Why are you like that?
我不会抱猫
I'm not good with cats.
老兄 怎么了
Hey, man. What's going on?
吉米 有一只…
Jimmy. Jimmy. We have a...
噢不
Oh, no!
我们要帮你取暖
We gotta warm you up, buddy!
是啊 小心点
Oh, yeah. Oh, be careful.
噢 糟了
Oh, no.
我抱住你了
-Oh, I've got you.
-牠好冰冷喔 -天啊
He's so cold.
要带牠去哪
Where do we go?
不行 牠身上有虫 奥托
-No. But no. Toxo. Otto. -Oh.
走吧 我抱住你了
Okay, let's go. I've got you now.
奥托 开门
Otto. Open the door.
没事了 小猫咪
Oh, it's all right, buddy.
-不会有事的 -真可怜
-It's gonna be okay, chiquitito. -Poor guy.
没事了
Okay. You're okay.
-地板全是雪 -抱歉
-Snow all over my floor. -Oh, sorry.
天啊 屋子里头好冷喔
Oh, my God, it's so freezing here.
这一件呢
-不行 -能不能…
Okay, how about this one? Please?
别碰那件大衣
No, no. Don't touch that coat. It'll stay here.
-能不能拿条毯子  -给那只猫
-Okay. Can you please bring a blanket? -For the cat?
没关系 我行的 你在干嘛
-It's okay. I got this. -What are you doing?
帮牠取暖啊 我的体温很高
Oh, body heat works wonders. I've got plenty of body and heat.
我去打开烤箱
I'm gonna turn on the oven.
不准把猫放进我的烤箱
You are not putting that cat in my oven.
我只想让屋子暖起来
No, I'm just trying to get some heat in the house.
流理台好低喔 哪里买的
Your counters are so low. Where did you get them?
我做的
I built them.
替我太太索妮娅量身打造
For Sonya. For my wife.
她也很矮吗
Ah. Is she short too?
索妮娅去世了
Sonya passed away.
她的厨艺很棒 对吧
She was a great cook though, wasn't she?
我以前常常来蹭饭
I used to eat here all the time.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
请你们离开
Well, can you go now?
我有事要做
I have things to do.
见到你真好
Well, it was great seeing ya, as usual.
谁要照顾这小家伙
Oh, hey, who's gonna look after this guy?
你啊
You are.
好吧
Okay.
现在好好向我求婚
Now ask me the right way.
真的超赞的
It was so beautiful too.
我现在饿了
Okay, now I'm hungry. Now I'm hungry.
"恭喜1978学年度工学院毕业班"
让我看看
Let's see.
"工学院"
大学董事会特此证明奥托安德森
"The Board of Regents hereby certifies that Otto Anderson,
完成工学院学士学位的学业…
having completed all the requirements for a Bachelor's Degree in Engineering--"
妳有没有想过要…
Would you ever wanna...
…想过要结婚
get married?
-如果妳想要… -看着我
-'Cause if you did... -Look at me.
现在好好向我求婚
Now ask me the right way.
妳愿意…
Will you...?
妳愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
愿意
Yes.
好啊
Yes!
-Yes.
好啊
Yes.
太好了
-Yes! Yes!
天啊 打电话给119
-Oh, my God! -Someone call 911.
他跌下去
He fell down!
-快去救他 -快拍 不 用录的
-Somebody help him! -Get the camera on him. No, take video.
真是够了
Oh, for God's sake.
-谁可以帮忙  -天啊 他跌下去了
-Who's gonna do something? -Oh, my God, he fell.
-谁去把他救上来 -你能动吗
-Get him off the tracks. Somebody help. -Hey! Can you move?
你得动起来 你得起来
You gotta move! Come on! You gotta get up!
谁来帮帮我
Will somebody help me?
快啊 快拍啊
-Come on. -Film it, film it, film it.
-快拍 -拍到了 我看到他了
-Get the shot. -I have him. I see him.
放大他的脸
Zoom in on his face.
-发生什么事 -我们要去博物馆…
-Tell me what happened. -We were going to the museum...
看着我
Look at me.
说哈啰
Say hello.
深呼吸 奥托
Take a breath, Otto.
握我的手
Take my hand.
握住我的手
Take my hand now!
你疯了吗 你可能因此丧命
Hey, are you out of your mind? You could have been killed.
先生 你救了他命
Sir, you saved his life.
他救了那家伙的命
He saved that guy's life.
你疯了 哦 我的天哪
You're amazing. Oh, my God.
真的太神奇了
That was amazing.
-随便啦 追踪我们 -追踪我们
-Whatever. Follow us. -Anyway, follow us.
嘿
Hey.
妳想把我吓死吗
Are you trying to scare me to death?
你看看
Look at this.
艾比想要画她的新邻居
Abbie wanted to make a picture of her new neighbour.
她要送给你
She wants you to have that.
那是你
That's you.
她总是把你画成彩色的
She always draws you in colour.
"总是"是什么意思
What do you mean, "always"?
我有个好主意
I have a very good idea.
你可以当我的驾驶教练
You can be my driver's instructor.
不要
No.
不不不
No, no, no.
我可没这闲工夫
I don't have time for that.
放心 我会付油钱
But don't worry, I'll pay for the gas and everything.
你们在这儿 我一直在找你们
Hey, there you guys are. I've been looking for ya everywhere.
嗨 吉米 你在干嘛
-Hi, Jimmy. What are you doing?
-猫在里面  -对
-Cat in there? -Yeah.
天啊 冷静点
-Oh, jeez! Calm down, dude.
牠真的很不喜欢这样
-He really doesn't like this.
把牠放出来
Let him out of the box.
好 抱歉 小兄弟
Okay. Sorry, buddy.
你在想什么 带他去散步
What do you think you were doing? Taking him for a walk?
我忘了我对猫过敏 得把牠带回来
Well, I had to bring him back. I forgot that I'm allergic.
所以…
-So...
-吉米 -是啊
-Oh, Jimmy. -Yeah. Yeah.
我涂了燕麦 但没有帮助
I put oatmeal on it, and it didn't help at all.
跟我来 汤米去年有条药膏
You know what, you come with me. Tommy has a prescription from last year.
-他捅了黄蜂窝 -妳确定
-He found a wasp's nest. -Are you sure?
-我不想麻烦妳 -没关系 别抓了
-I don't want to be a bother. -It's okay.
我应该多抓一下
-Don't scratch. -I feel like I should scratch a little.
嘿 这只猫呢
Hey, hey, what about the cat?
牠是你的了 奥托
Uh, looks like he's yours now, Otto.
好好爱牠
Love him.
进去箱子里
-Get in the box.
Get in the box.
进去箱子里
抱歉我还没去找妳
Sorry I haven't come yet.
比我想像的更困难
It's been harder than I thought to...
现在牠又搬进来
And now he's moved in.
我养了一只猫
I have a cat.
我得先想办法处理牠
I have to figure out what to do with him.
然后就去找妳 索妮娅 我保证
Then I'll come to you, Sonya. I promise.
我好想妳
I miss you.
♪ And I finally see ♪
♪ How your love is the best of me ♪
♪ Yeah, there's so much I want you to know ♪
♪ Guess I'll wait till you're home ♪
噢 不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
你不准占领我的床
You are not taking over my bed.
这才是你的床
This is your bed.
你想睡在外面 睡在雪堆里吗
Would you rather sleep outside,
back in the snow?
我可以安排
That can be arranged.
你会是这世上最棒的爸爸
You'll be the best dad our children could ever hope for.
嘿
Hey! Hey!
怎么了
What?
你骑脚踏车发传单
Is this what you use that bike for?
对啊 这是我的工作
Yeah. It's my job.
当服务生或加油站员工才是工作
Waiting tables and pumping gas, that's a job.
我晚上在披萨店 周末在二手店打工…
I also work nights at a pizza shop and weekends at a thrift store, so...
你是安德森先生 对吧
-Huh. -You're Mr Anderson, aren't you?
你以前会去学校
You used to come to presentations at school.
什么时候
When was that?
安德森太太是我的老师
Mrs Anderson was my teacher.
她是第一个没有把我当怪咖的人
She was the first person that didn't treat me like a freak
因为我是跨性别
'cause I'm transgender.
她是第一个叫我新名字的人
She was the first to call me by my new name.
说服其他老师也那么做
She got the other teachers to do it too.
在学校帮了我很多
It really helped me at school.
我不会再发你传单了
I won't leave these here anymore.
嘿
Hey.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
-马尔坎
-Malcolm.
我是奥托
Otto.
幸会了 奥托
Nice to meet you, Otto.
嘿
Hey!
奥托 好消息
Otto! Good news.
安迪在教我开车
Andy's teaching me how to drive.
他教错了
The wrong way.
-谢谢你 -不客气
-Thank you. -Of course.
-好吧 -很好
-All right. -Okay.
-掰
-Bye.
打P档
Park!
你还在打D档 那是自排车
You're still in drive! It's an automatic.
你还在打D档 应该打P档
You were still in drive. You gotta put it into park.
什么
In what?
掰
Bye!
-救命啊 -我来了
-Help! -I'm coming!
我来救公主了
Saving the princess!
好啦 来了 奥托
-All right. Coming! -Otto!
奥托来了 我妈做了饼干
Otto's here! My mom made her salpores.
奥托 请进
Hey, Otto. Come in.
我无法忍受白痴教白痴如何开车
I can't stand watching one idiot teach another how to drive.
妳 穿上大衣 该上课了
You. Put on your coat. It's lesson time.
什么
What?
你要教我 真假
You're gonna teach me? Really?
奥托 谢谢你
Otto, thank you!
谢谢你
-Mm. -Thank you.
我马上就来
I'll be right out!
你真好心 谢谢你
That's really, really nice of you, Otto. Thank you.
我试过一次
I tried once.
我出门啰
You guys, okay.
掰 奥托
Bye, Otto!
-妈妈要去开车 -小心点
-Mama's going on a ride. -Be careful, honey.
-掰 妈妈 -掰 乖女儿
-Bye, Mama! -Bye, mi vida.
玩得开心
-Have fun, guys!
掰 妈妈
Bye, Mama!
太好了
All right.
没有大人了 来吧
-No more grown-ups. Come on! -Yay!
奥托 开我们的车好吗
Ah. Otto, pero can we go in our car?
我只开过自排车
Because I've only ever driven automatic.
不行
No.
我要教妳怎么开车 上车
I'm teaching you how to drive. Get in.
前面是红灯 妳得刹车
Now, coming up on the red light. You're going to have to stop.
我得踩离合器 对吧
Okay, but I get the clutch, right?
先踩离合器再踩刹车
You get the clutch and then press in on the brake.
-踩刹车或离合器  -踩离合器
-Do I hit the brake or the clutch? -No, keep the clutch in.
先踩刹车再踩离合器
Put in the brake, I put the clutch.
先踩离合器 现在踩刹车
Clutch and brake. And now brake.
刹车 刹车
-Brake. Brake. -No. No.
别对我大叫 我没对妳大叫
-Don't shout at me. -I am not shouting at you.
我踩离合器了
Clutch in. It's in, it's in!
我们要停车 然后…
We're going to stop, and...
先踩离合器再踩刹车 踩刹车
Clutch in, and brake. Brake. Brake. Brake.
他停车了 别撞上去 刹车刹车
The car is stopped. Don't hit the car! Brake, brake!
好了 放手
Yes. All right, let go.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
刹车
Brake.
先踩离合器再踩刹车
It's clutch and brake.
我逊毙了
I suck at this.
-逊毙了 -妳还在学
-I suck. -You're learning.
我差点撞到它 只差一点点
Oh, my God, I almost hit the car. It's like this.
没关系啦 那是台油电车
It doesn't matter. It's a hybrid.
那是台油电车
It's a hybrid, okay.
-我该倒车 -不用
-Okay, I should move back. -No, no, no. No.
-没关系 -我差点撞到它
-You're fine right where you are. -But I'm very close.
-无所谓 -不必倒车吗
-Doesn't matter. -I don't need to go back?
先等绿灯
-Just wait for the green light.
走吧 先踩离合器
And here we go. So press in on the clutch.
再踩油门
And give it a little gas.
慢慢松开离合…
Slowly let out on the clu--
妳没有入档
Oh, you're not in gear.
绿灯
Green!
先踩离合器再换档…不必转动钥匙
Press in on the clutch, shift into fi-- You don't have to turn the key.
-快走啊 -慢慢踩…
-Go! -Just press in--
-天啊 -慢慢踩…
-Oh, my God. -Press in on the--
先松开离合器再踩油门
-Slowly let out the clutch,
我办不到
-then press the gas. -I can't do this.
-就这么简单 -我办不到
-That is all you have to do. -I can't do this.
不要 奥托
No, Otto. Otto, no.
什么
What?
哦 可恶
Oh, shit.
你有什么毛病
What is wrong with you?
她正在学开车
She's learning how to drive.
你不必学开车吗
Did you not have to learn how to drive?
冷静点 老头儿 嘿
Calm down, old man. Hey, hey.
我不是老头儿 王八蛋
I'm not your old man! You son of a bitch!
你敢再按一次喇叭
If you honk that horn one more time,
你就死定了 听到吗
it'll be the last thing you do. You hear me? Huh?
了解吗
¿Comprende?
噢 惨了
Oh, shit.
妳给我听好
Now you listen to me.
妳生过两个小孩 就快生第三个
You have given birth to two children. Soon it'll be three.
妳从很远的国家来到这里
You have come here from a country very far away.
学会新的语言
You learned a new language,
上学念书 嫁了个笨老公
you got yourself an education and a nitwit husband
妳把全家照顾得好好的
and you are holding that family together.
学会开车绝对没问题
You will have no problem learning how to drive.
天啊 世上有一大堆白痴
My God, the world is full of complete idiots
都能学会开车 妳又不是白痴
who have managed to figure it out, and you are not a complete idiot.
所以…
So...
踩离合器
Clutch.
换档
Shift.
踩油门
Gas.
开车
Drive.
太好了
Que bueno.
这是个停车位
Okay, there's a spot right there.
练习路边停车
Just pull up, parallel,
先倒车 直到保险杆和照后镜对齐
and back the car up until that bumper is in line with your side-view mirror.
"史丹格烘焙店"
现在打直
Now straighten out.
把车子倒进路边
Back up all the way up to the curb.
-向前一点 -再向前一点
-A little bit. -Well, a little bit.
然后停车
And stop.
打N档
Neutral.
拉手刹车
-Brake.
车钥匙
Key.
就这样
Is that it?
That's it.
时间刚刚好
-And we're right on time.
我来吧
I have it.
这些是萨姆拉面包
-These are semlors.
瑞典的闪电泡芙
-Swedish éclairs. -Oh!
小心会爆浆
They're a little messy.
吃吃看吧
-But let's try. -Yes.
用手指拿
With your finger.
你怎么找到这地方
How did you find this place?
这是索妮娅的爱店
This was Sonya's place.
我们以前每周六下午一点都会来
We used to come here every Saturday at- 00.
然后做什么
And then? What?
两点钟回家
Go home at- 00.
我会洗车打蜡
I'd wash and wax the car,
她会改考卷做饭 然后看一整天的书
and she would grade her papers and cook and spend the rest of the day reading.
什么样的书
What kind of books?
她的书
-Her books.
我尝试看过 但是…
I tried to read some of them, but...
我就是…
I'm just...
我不爱看书
I'm not into books.
她朋友说我们天差地远
Her friends said that we were like night and day.
我遇见索妮娅之前的人生是黑白的
My life was black-and-white before I met Sonya.
她增添了色彩
She was the colour.
我一定会喜欢她
I would have liked her.
她真的很有个性
She was a force of nature.
说服学校为需要辅导的学生
She convinced the school to start up a programme
特地开一门课
for the kids that needed extra help.
很多孩子家庭有问题
A lot of kids had problems at home
或是不善于社交
or, uh, social anxieties.
但经过索妮娅的辅导
But by the time Sonya was done with 'em,
他们都会读莎翁
they were reciting Shakespeare.
我遇到她以前的学生…
I ran into one of her students,
就在前几天
just the other day.
他叫马尔坎
A kid named Malcolm.
-妳需要奶精
You need more cream.
-好
Okay.
我们刚搬去的时候相处得很融洽
We all got along fine, of course, when we first moved in.
就像天赐的礼物
It was like a gift.
欢迎搬进这个社区
Welcome to the neighbourhood.
-嗨 我是索妮娅 -我是安妮塔
-Hi, I'm Sonya. -I'm Anita.
索妮娅和安妮塔是闺蜜
Sonya and Anita were best friends.
我拿着罗赖把
So I got my Allen keys...
我和鲁本其实很像
And Reuben and I were a lot alike.
骑慢一点
Hey! Slow down!
各方面都很像
About most things.
白痴
Idiot.
但人都会变
But people change.
或是不会变
Or they don't change.
世事无常 我们越来越疏远
Things happen. People drift apart.
筑起心墙 他们不高兴
They build walls. They take offence.
"福特"
我们都知道原因
Who knows why.
也许建商一直盖房子把大家逼疯
Maybe it was all the construction that drove everybody crazy.
那个山丘上本来有一座树林
You know, there used to be a forest up on that hill.
所以才命名桦木社区
That's why they call it Birchwood.
后来他们加盖公寓
Then they started building all those condos
砍光桦木
and cut down all the birches.
我们开始抗议他们才知道做了什么
They didn't even realise what they were doing until we told them,
我和鲁本
Reuben and I.
这是在他把你踢走之前
But this was before the coup?
对啊 我和鲁本当时还是朋友
Oh, yeah, yeah. Reuben and I were friends then.
后来我们就意见不合
After that, all we saw were the differences.
"福特"
"雪佛兰"
几年后 他们的儿子克里斯去日本工作
A few years later, their son, Chris, he, uh, took a job in Japan,
后来他再也没回来看他们
and I don't think he's been back to visit them since.
他和鲁本一直处不来
-Oh. -Reuben and he never did get along.
于是我就决定放下前嫌
Anyway, that's when I decided to bury the hatchet.
鲁本
Reuben.
嘿
Hey.
前阵子索妮娅给我这瓶酒
Sonya gave me this a while back.
没机会打开来喝
Never found the occasion.
也许我们能重新开始
I thought maybe we could start fresh.
想看我的新车吗
Hey, would you like to see my new car?
好啊
Sure.
全新车款
It's a new model.
才刚出来不久
Just came out.
你看
Voilà.
丰田
A Toyota?
你买了一台丰田
You bought a Toyota.
敞篷轿跑车
Celica GT convertible.
五速自排车
Five-speed automatic.
你得跟着时代改变
You gotta change with the times.
奥托
Otto!
我不知道他是怎么了 但我失去了他
I don't know what went wrong with Reuben, but that's when I knew I'd lost him.
我得捍卫我相信的事
I mean, a man has to stand up for what he believes in.
就算是一台福特汽车
Even if it is an F-O-R-D.
你和索妮娅想过要生小孩吗
And you and Sonya, did you ever think about having children?
两点了
Well,- 00.
好吧
Okay.
来了
Yes.
我今晚想请你帮忙
I was wondering if you could help us out tonight.
我和汤米在宝宝出生前
Me and Tommy don't get a lot of time to go out for dinner
很少出去吃晚饭
before the baby comes.
我才不会载你们去约会
I'm not gonna drive you two around on a date.
不用啦 我们会叫计程车
No. We're gonna take a cab.
那妳要我帮什么忙
What do you need me for, then?
妈 我没拿
-Mama, I did not! Why would I? -Yes, you did!
才怪 还给我
-Give it back! -You gotta catch me!
-来抓我啊 -够了 别再吵了
You guys, por favor.
妳们要学会分享一切
And learn to share your everything.
我不确定耶
I'm not sure about this.
别傻了 这会很好玩
No. Don't be silly. It's gonna be very fun.
请记住 艾比九点得上床
If you remember, Abbie has to be in bed by- 00, okay?
可以吧
-You're good?
警报器密码是4491
So, alarm code, 4491. 4491.
我要设定为防盗模式 你有在专心看吗
I'm setting it to "Armed Stay." Are you paying attention?
你想出去只要按这个按钮
So if you wanna go out,
就能解除警报器
you just have to press this button here, and it's disalarmed.
我会待在屋里
I'll be right here.
是喔 好吧
Right. Yeah.
以防万一
Well, you never know.
-对奥托阿公好一点
Be good to Abuelo Otto please, okay?
-会啦
We will!
我没看到巧克力牛奶
I don't see chocolate milk in here.
要加巧克力酱 但加太多她会睡不着
You make it with the syrup. But not too much. It'll keep her awake.
牛奶给我
Give me milk.
那是什么
What is that?
一点都没用的洗碗机
That's the goddamn useless dishwasher.
爸爸说他想把它丢出窗户
Dad said he wanted to throw it out the window,
但妈妈说爸爸不准再开窗户
but Mom said Dad isn't allowed to open windows anymore.
头
Head.
卡贝沙
Cabeza.
-卡贝沙
-Cabeza.
很好
Good.
眼睛
Eyes.
欧呼
Ojos.
-欧胡
-Ojos.
很好
Good.
手臂 贝拉索
Arm. Brazo.
很好
Good.
我觉得这不是好主意
I don't think this is a good idea.
为什么
Why?
因为没人打得赢摔角手
Because no one stands a chance against a luchadoro.
摔角手阿公
Abuelo Luchadoro!
救救我
Help me, help me.
等等 是他先打人的
Wait, no, he started it.
-预备 -开打啰
-Ready? -Rub it and smack!
用力打 空手劈
Rub it and smack! Smack! Karate chop!
"安第斯大学 玛丽索曼德兹"
"加州大学 玛丽索曼德兹"
呃
Huh.
哇 好安静喔
Wow, it's awfully quiet, huh?
大伙儿
-Hey, guys.
嗨
Hi.
她已经睡着了
She was already asleep.
怎么样
How was it?
-很好啊 -你今晚做得很棒 奥托
-Fine. -You did a good job tonight, Otto.
用这个拍拍你的背
You should pat yourself on the back.
-谢谢你 奥托 -不客气
-Thank you, Otto. -Yeah.
出门
Exit now.
晚安
Have a good night.
好吧
Okay.
他怎么办到的
How did he do that?
-嗨 奥托 -马尔坎
-Hi, Otto. -Malcolm.
换档的时候听不到落链声吗
You can't hear your chain rattle when you switch gears like that?
-太旧了 -别怪脚踏车
-My bike's getting old. -Don't blame the bike.
只要调整拨链器
You just have to adjust your derailleur.
-什么  -你要调整拨链器
-My what? -Your derailleur needs adjusting.
不好意思
Uh, excuse me.
-嗨 我是雪莉肯锡 -嗨
-Hi, I'm Shari Kenzie. -Hi.
我是社群媒体记者
I'm a social media journalist.
我在找奥托安德森
I'm, um, looking for Otto Anderson.
妳确定要找他
Are you sure you wanna do that?
太棒了 真是不可思议
Wow. It's great. That's amazing.
好好对待它 它会让你骑得很顺
You treat it right, it'll treat you right.
拿去 留着吧
Here. Keep the set.
谢了 奥托
Thanks, Otto.
我竟然帮你丢垃圾到别人家的草坪
I can't believe I'm helping you throw crap onto people's lawns.
打两份工不够吗
Isn't two jobs enough?
我在存钱买车子
I'm saving up for a car.
-是吗  -是啊
-Yeah? -Yeah.
哪个牌子
What kind?
福斯
Volkswagen.
小姐 妳挡住车库了
Young lady, you're blocking the garage.
安德森先生 我是雪莉肯锡
Mr Anderson? My name is Shari Kenzie.
我是社群媒体记者 我…
I'm a social media journalist, and I--
那是什么
What is that?
我有个网路节目叫"日常英雄"
I have an online series called Everyday Heroes.
你那天在火车站真的很勇敢
What you did the other day at the train station was amazing.
你救了那个人
You saved that man's life.
妳找错人了
You have the wrong guy.
并没有 我看过影片十几次
No, I don't. I've watched the video at least a dozen times.
-就是你 -影片
-It's you. -Video?
你还没看过
You haven't seen it?
有个通勤族拍下来放上网路
Oh. A commuter recorded what happened on their phone and posted it online.
留言区有人认得你 我这才找到你
Someone in the comments recognised you. That's how I tracked you down.
影片有一百多万人次观看
It's gotten over a million views.
一百万 一百万
A million? A million.
他们为什么要多管闲事
Why can't people mind their own business?
因为你的故事激励人心
Because stories like yours are inspiring.
我只想跟你聊一下…
If I could just talk to you for a few minutes--
不行 我有太多事情要做
No, now I've got too many things I have to do.
我拍下你救的人的影片
I recorded a video message from the man you saved.
你应该看看
You should see this.
-奥托 -让我找出来
-Um... just pull it up. -Otto! Hi!
早安
Good morning.
准备再教我开车吗
-So you ready for another driving lesson?
-现在不方便 -是吗
-Now's not a good time. -No?
有人吗 我还在里面
Hello? Hello? Hey, I'm still in here!
-我没把妳锁起来 -有人吗
-I didn't lock you in. -Hello?
转一下把手就能开门
Turn the knob, open the door.
妳有开过门吧
-Opened a door before, haven't you?
白痴
Idiot.
奥托 是我
Otto! It's me.
她走了
She's gone.
很好 我还没巡逻完
Good. I'm not through with my rounds.
社群媒体记者
"Social media journalist"?
那是什么意思
What the hell does that even mean?
一群笨蛋拿着手机自拍
Buncha knotheads pointin' a camera at themselves.
你处理得很好
I thought you handled it really well.
把她关进你的车库
I mean, closing her in your garage.
那一招真的很赞
That was, like, excellent strategy.
好样的
-Good job.
奥托 我在想 你帮了我们这么多
Otto, also, I was thinking you've done so much for us.
-我想为你做点事 -不需要
-I wanna do something for you too. -I don't need anything.
你可以吃好一点 有时候
Well, I think you could do with some decent food. Sometimes. No?
-那些饼干…
Those cookies...
-沙波洛
The what? The "salporanz"?
那些不错吃 还不错
Those are not bad. They're not bad.
我也在想
And, also, I was thinking
我可以帮你清理家里和玄关
that I can help you clean out your house and clean out the front hall in your home,
帮你打包索妮娅的大衣和鞋子
and help you pack the coats and shoes you have there of Sonya's.
不需要
That's not needed.
是啦 但这能帮你走出来
No, but it can help you move on.
我不想走出来
I don't wanna move on.
她永远都会陪着你
She's always gonna be with you.
但你还在这里
-But you're still here. -Ah...
够了
That's enough.
我爸死后 我妈就放弃生活
When my father died, my mother, she stopped living.
-她不再像以前那样… -别说了
-She just stopped like she used-- -Stop talking!
-闭嘴 -好啦 别对我大叫
-Stop it. -Okay! Don't yell at me.
为什么要多管闲事
白痴
Why can't people mind their own business? Idiots.
逮到机会就来烦我
Interrupting me at every turn.
他们一直喋喋不休 盖过我对她的回忆
The more they babble, the more they drown out the memory of her voice.
我不想把索妮娅赶出我的生命
I don't want to clear Sonya from my life.
她是我的所有
She was everything.
我本来一无所有 她走后更是如此
There was nothing before her, and there's nothing after!
你有我
I'm something.
那个王八蛋
That son of a bitch!
不不不
Uh-uh. No, no, no.
呃呃呃
Uh-uh-uh. Uh-uh-uh.
停车 给我停车
Stop right there. You stop that car!
你把铁门打开 对吧
Did you leave that gate open? You left that gate open, didn't you?
只有你还在乎
You're the only one who gives a damn.
我要住户遵守规定
I give a damn about people following the rules.
我知道你的事
Yes, I know. I know all about you.
你在办公室的档案很厚
There's a file on you at the office. It's this thick.
我知道你老婆的事
I know about your wife.
你怪每个人…
How you blame whatever happened to her on everybody else.
给我闭嘴
You shut up.
别再说一个字
Don't you say one more word.
别激动 奥托 我不想惹你生气
Take it easy, Otto. Look, I'm not trying to upset you,
但你不该一个人生活
but you really shouldn't be living alone.
我们比你想像的更了解你 所以…
I mean, we know more about you than you probably realise, so...
照顾好你的心脏 好吗
Just look after that heart of yours, okay?
你对我的心脏了解多少
What do you know about my heart?
Hey, what do you know about my heart?!
多管闲事的混蛋
You prying bastard!
奥托
Otto, Otto.
怎么了 没事吧 还好吧
Otto, what's going on? Are you okay? Do you feel okay?
想帮我的话就关上铁门
You wanna help me, close the gate.
奥托
Otto. Otto.
-Otto.
奥托
Otto.
拜托跟我说话 奥托
Talk to me, Otto. Please?
奥托
Otto.
跟我说话 奥托
Talk to me, Otto.
奥托
Otto.
谢谢你
Thank you.
"尼加拉大瀑布"
你戴会很帅
It'll be cute on you.
-不要 -来嘛
-No. -Aw, c'mon.
老公 你真的很帅
Honey, you look really cute.
"雾中少女号"
把手给我
Give me your hand.
宝宝正在踢我
The baby's really kicking.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ A-ha, ooh ♪
♪ I know you have a little life In you yet ♪
♪ I know you have a lot of strength left ♪
索妮娅
Sonya!
♪ I know you have a lot of strength left ♪
索妮娅
Sonya!
♪ I should be crying But I just can't let it show ♪
♪ I should be hoping But I can't stop thinking ♪
♪ Of all the things I should've said That I never said ♪
♪ All the things we should've done ♪
索妮娅
Sonya!
♪ That we never did ♪
♪ All the things I should've given But I didn't ♪
♪ Oh, darling ♪
♪ Make it go ♪
♪ Make it go away ♪
♪ Give me your hand ♪
♪ I know you have a little life In you yet ♪
♪ I know you have a lot of strength left ♪
♪ I should be crying But I just can't let it show ♪
♪ I should be hoping But I can't stop thinking ♪
嗨
Hi.
♪ Oh ♪
妳醒来了
There you are.
♪ Of all the things we should've said That we never said ♪
♪ All the things we should've done That we never did ♪
♪ Oh, darling, make it go away ♪
♪ Just make it go away now ♪
那就够了 亲爱的
That's enough now, darling.
你很愤怒 我知道
You're angry. I know.
而且悲伤
And sad.
我也是
So am I.
但我们得继续过活
But now we have to live.
又怎么了
What now?
马尔坎
Malcolm.
抱歉 我不是故意…
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to--
我不会向你开枪
I'm not gonna shoot you.
那是什么声音
What was that noise?
发电机坏了 停电了
The generator blew and the power is out.
你想干嘛 外面很冷
What d'ya want? It's freezing.
我想请你让我睡你沙发
I was hoping you might let me crash on your couch for the night.
这里不是旅馆
This is not a hotel.
对 很抱歉
No. I'm sorry.
你为什么不能回家
Why can't you go home?
我爸把我赶出家门
My dad kicked me out.
你可以睡沙发
There's a sofa you can use.
别去餐厅 天花板需要修理
Don't go into the dining room. The ceiling needs repair.
就在楼上索妮娅以前的书房
It's upstairs in Sonya's old study.
他为什么把你踢出家门
So why did he kick you out?
因为你现在是马尔坎了
Because you're Malcolm now?
对 因为我是马尔坎
Yeah, because I'm Malcolm.
因为我打扮成这样
Because I dress like this.
我看太多书 我不爱运动 随你挑
I read too much. I don't like sports. Take your pick.
我是跨性别他觉得很丢脸
He's embarrassed 'cause I'm trans.
那他就是个白痴
Then he's an idiot.
你今晚睡这里
This is you.
别乱碰东西
Try not to touch anything.
好的
Okay.
真没想到
Well...
早安
Good morning. The power's still out
还在停电 我就把剩下的蛋煮完
so I cooked up the last of the eggs while they're still good.
趁还没有坏之前 希望你不会介意
Hope you don't mind.
我得去巡逻了
I have to do my rounds.
不先喝杯咖啡
Don't you at least want some coffee first?
好的
Yes.
来吧
There you go.
吃点炒蛋吗
Uh, some eggs?
我不会拒绝
I wouldn't say no.
好吧
All right.
那个罐子…
That can...
放进这里
goes in here.
挂起来
Hang that up.
奥托 你在巡逻喔
Hey, Otto! Making your rounds.
我能加入吗 我得多走路
You mind if I join you? I need to get my steps in.
好吧
-Okay.
-我是吉米 -马尔坎
-I'm Jimmy. -Malcolm.
-幸会了 -谢了
-Nice to meet you. -Aw, thanks.
有
Yes.
奥托 走慢一点 我的心跳太快了
Hey, Otto, if you want to slow down, we can 'cause my beats are up.
有
Yes.
有听说他们要把鲁本送去护理之家吗
Otto, did you hear they're moving Reuben into assisted living this afternoon?
谁
Who is?
建商的人啊
The Dye & Merika guys.
天啊
-My God.
他们说服安妮塔卖掉房子
They convinced Anita to sell the house.
不 是克里斯的决定
No, they made the deal with Chris.
-他不能那么做 -他可以
-Chris? He can't do that. -Yeah, he can.
建商发现安妮塔得了帕金森氏症
After Dye & Merika found out Anita had Parkinson's,
就找到克里斯然后…
they tracked Chris down and--
-帕金森氏症  -对
-Parkinson's? -Yeah.
去年克里斯说服安妮塔签了授权书
So last year Chris convinced Anita to give him power of attorney
以防她的状况变糟
in case she got worse.
于是建商就向克里斯买下房子
So Dye & Merika made the deal with Chris to buy the house.
那群混蛋
Those pricks.
等等 安妮塔去年发现自己有帕金森
Wait, Anita found out she had Parkinson's last year?
不可能是这样
No, that's not right.
她会告诉索妮娅 索妮娅会告诉我
She would've told Sonya. Sonya would've told me.
安妮塔和鲁本不想让你们知道
Well, Anita and Reuben didn't want you and Sonya to know.
他们说你已经够忙了
They said you had enough on your plate as it is.
他们那么说
They said that?
我要看建商给妳的所有文件
I need to see everything you ever got from Dye & Merika.
通知 信件 妳有授权书副本吗
Notices, letters. Do you have a copy of the power of attorney?
你怎么会知道
How do you know about that?
-妳有吗  -有
-Do you have it? -Yes.
-去拿来 -好
-Get it. -Yes.
还有妳和鲁本病情的纪录
And any records of Reuben's condition and yours.
都是吉米跟你说的
Did Jimmy tell you that?
妳能去拿吗
Can you get it now?
可以
Yes.
我是个白痴
I've been an idiot.
纠结于自己的烦恼 不再替别人着想
I got so wrapped up in my own troubles, I stopped thinking of anyone else.
我以为可以置身事外
And I figured they weren't thinking about me.
朋友不该这么冷漠
Friends shouldn't do that.
所以…
So...
过了这么久很难开口
This isn't easy to say after all this time.
但我很抱歉
But I'm sorry.
我也会搞定这件事
And I will sort all this out.
我得借用妳的手机
I need to use your phone.
为何不能用你自己的
Why can't you use your own?
我的手机停话了
Mine is disconnected at the moment.
为什么
-Why? -That doesn't matter.
不重要 我得借用妳的手机
I just need to use your phone, okay?
你知道吗
You know what?
不行
No.
-不行  -不行
-No? -No.
你不肯说你的手机为何停话
You won't tell me why your phone is disconnected?
也不肯说为何要借用我的手机
You won't tell me why you need to use my phone?
更不肯说你昨天在街上怎么了
You won't tell me what happened to you in the street yesterday?
然后回家连门都不肯打开
And then you went inside and you wouldn't even open the door?
你把我吓坏了 奥托
You scared me, Otto.
你知道我在门外等了多久吗
Do you know how long I was out there?
我不知道你是不是出了事
And I didn't know if something had happened to you.
或是你会出什么事
Or if something was gonna happen to you.
很抱歉我提到索妮娅的大衣
And I'm sorry if I said the wrong thing about Sonya's coats.
但我只是想帮忙
But I was just trying to help.
你却把我拒之门外
And you left me out there.
所以你不能借用我的手机
So, no. You can't use my phone.
你觉得大家都是白痴所以人生很难
You think your life is so hard because everybody's an idiot
你得自己扛下所有事 对吗
and you have to do everything on your own, right?
对吗
Right?
猜怎么着
But guess what.
你办不到
You can't.
没人办得到
No one can.
你应该感到高兴
And I think you should just be happy
有人想帮你度过糟糕的一天
that someone was trying to help you get through a crappy day.
就算他们是白痴
Even if they're an idiot.
所以…建商那些混蛋
-So... -The real estate bastards
想把安妮塔和鲁本赶出他们家
are trying to force Anita and Reuben out of their home.
所以我才得借用妳的手机
That's why I need to use your phone.
好吧 进来吧
Okay, fine. Come on.
我们从来没度过假
We had never had a vacation.
索妮娅怀胎六个月
Sonya was six months pregnant.
她想趁宝宝出生前做点特别的
And she wanted to do something special before the baby came.
于是我们就决定去尼加拉大瀑布
So we booked a trip to Niagara Falls.
回程时客运出车祸
On the way back, the bus crashed.
车厂召回刹车线
There'd been a recall on the brake lines,
但客运公司从没修好
but the company never had them fixed.
索妮娅半身瘫痪 而且…
Sonya was paralyzed...
我们也失去了儿子
and we lost our son.
三个月后她终于能回家
After three months, she was finally able to come home.
但他们已经开始盖新公寓
But they had started building the new condos
还有社区中心和步道
and the community centre and the walkways,
全都不是无障碍空间
none of which were designed for people in wheelchairs.
建商大可以修改设计蓝图
The builders could have changed their plans.
但法律没这规定 他们也不在乎
But the laws weren't in place back then, and they didn't care.
我在乎
I did.
我非常在乎
-We're putting in a new playground... -I cared.
-你太太这种人… -我好生气
-There's places for people like your wife. -And I was so angry.
什么意思 她这种人 什么意思
What does that mean? People like her? What does that mean?
-你想说什么  -放开我
-What're you tryin' to say?! -Get off of me!
于是他们就把我踢出管委会
That's when they voted me out as head of the homeowners' association.
我想彻底毁掉他们
I wanted to obliterate them all.
建商 房地商 客运公司和司机
The builders, and the realtors, and the bus company, the bus driver.
我本来永远无法放手…
I never would have let it go...
要是没有索妮娅
but for Sonya.
索妮娅说我们必须继续过活
Sonya said we had to keep living.
我就那么做
That's what I did.
我为了索妮娅继续过活
I lived for Sonya.
她半年前去世
Six months ago she passed away.
癌症
Cancer.
我本来也想寻死
I was going to join her.
所以才会停用手机
That's why I had them disconnect my phone.
但现在我觉得她要我继续过活
But now I think she wants me to keep living.
我也有事要做
And I have things to do.
"雪莉肯锡"
你在浪费时间 奥托
You're wasting your time, Otto.
木已成舟 鲁本要跟我们走
It's a done deal. Reuben's coming with us.
你敢挡路
And if you get in our way,
我就请警察逮捕你
I'll have you arrested.
我什么都没做 别再向前走一步
-I'm not doing a thing. -Don't you take another step.
你不能把我先生带走
You are not taking my husband away from me.
安妮塔 我们这是为妳好
Anita, please. We're doing this for your own good.
你想抢走我的房子
What you're doing is trying to take my property.
我要鲁本 留下来跟我一起…
I want Reuben to stay right here for the rest of his life,
"长照部门"
…在家度过余生
with me in our home.
妳不行了 谁会照顾鲁本
Okay, but who's gonna take care of Reuben when you're no longer able to?
谁会照顾妳 奥托
Who's gonna take care of you? Otto?
奥托的身体也不行了 对吧
Otto's not in the best health either. Are you, Otto?
我会照顾他们
I'll take care of 'em.
你在干嘛 放下来 安妮塔和鲁本就像我的家人
-What are you doing? Put that down. -Anita and Reuben are like family to me.
只要他们需要 我就会照顾他们
I'll take care of them as long as they need.
他们不是你家人
They're not your family.
他们的儿子克里斯决定他们无法自理
Uh, their son, Chris, has decided they're not fit enough to be on their own,
所以我们只是…
and so what we're doing is--
不好意思 克里斯上次见他父母是何时
Excuse me. When was the last time Chris saw his parents?
他住在日本 十年没跟父母联络
He lives in Japan. They've been estranged for 10 years.
克里斯不清楚他父母的状况
Chris would have no idea how his parents are doing,
除了你跟他说的
except for what you told him.
妳又是谁
Okay. And who are you?
我是雪莉肯锡
My name is Shari Kenzie.
社群媒体记者
Social media journalist.
我们现在正在直播
-We're streaming live right now. -Uh...
够了…关掉摄影机 不准乱拍
All right, all right, shut that camera off. You can't film this.
人行道是公共区域
It's a public sidewalk.
你跟安妮塔儿子说她得了帕金森 但…
You told Anita's son, Chris, that she had Parkinson's,
她从来没说过她的诊断结果
but Anita never told anyone about her diagnosis.
你怎么会知道
So how did you know?
我得查一下记录
I'd have to check the records.
安德森先生算是本地英雄
Mr Anderson over there is something of a local hero.
他说你也知道他的私人就诊资料
He tells me you know details about his private health records as well.
你和你公司
So how are you and your company
是怎么非法取得老人家的病历
getting illegal access to the medical records of seniors?
好了 走吧 这件事结束了
Okay, let's go. We're done. We're done.
幸会了
Very nice to meet you.
你玩完了
No, you're done. You're done!
别拿手机拍我 再见
-Get that goddamn camera out of my face. -Goodbye.
-我们做到了 -没错
-We did it! -Oh, we did!
掰 谢谢你
Bye, thank you!
我一个小时前上传安妮塔和克里斯的故事
I first uploaded Anita and Chris's story an hour ago.
已经有几十个人说
Already dozens of people are saying
建商把他们赶出自己的家
Dye & Merika forced them out of their homes.
-太简单了 -慢走不送
-That was easy. -Yeah, goodbye.
如果你有故事 请和我雪莉肯锡分享
If you have a story, share it with me at Shari_Kenzie.
拍到了 拍到了
-I got it. I got it.
嘿 你忘了关铁门
Hey, you forgot to shut the gate!
看到没 他马上举手投降
You see that? He just rolled right over. Gave up.
当年那群混蛋至少会反抗
In our day, the bastards would at least put up a fight.
他们还没把我们赶走
They haven't gotten rid of us yet.
是啊
Yeah.
感觉很好 对吧
It does feel pretty good. Doesn't it?
敦亲睦邻已经过时了吗
Neighbourly neighbours, a thing of the past?
我正在访问目击者安妮塔和吉米
Well, I'm here with eyewitnesses Anita and Jimmy to find out more.
吉米 你说安妮塔和鲁本就像你的家人
Jimmy, you mentioned that Anita and Reuben are like family to you.
那到底是什么意思
What does that mean, exactly?
我几乎每晚都去他们家吃晚饭
Well, I have dinner at their house nearly every single night.
我知道你在等什么 吃午饭对吧
I know what you're waiting for. You're ready for lunch, aren't you?
我知道你要什么
I know what you want.
来吧
Whoa. Here we go.
你们最近才搬来 感觉如何
You moved into this community recently.
真的很棒
-How has that been for you? -It's been beautiful.
有这些好邻居…
And your family, to have people there that are--
是啊
Yeah.
奥托
-Otto? -Will you air this in Mexico?
Otto!
快叫救护车
Call an ambulance!
曼德兹太太 可以见他了
-Ms Mendes? You can see him now. -Yes?
好的
Yes. Yeah.
哈啰 奥托阿公
Hola, Abuelo Otto.
曼德兹太太
Ms Mendes?
我是艾利斯医师
I'm Dr Ellis.
安德森先生把妳列为最近的亲属
Mr Anderson listed you as next of kin.
是的 没错
Yes. Yes, that's correct.
妳叔叔有惊无险 他提过他的病情吗
Your uncle had a close call. Has he spoken to you about his condition?
其实并没有
No, not really. No.
这叫做肥厚性心肌症
It's called hypertrophic cardiomyopathy.
他的心太大了
Basically, his heart is too big.
太大了
Too big?
好吧
Oh, okay.
抱歉 没事
No, sorry. It's okay.
你真的很不会死耶
You're really bad at dying, you know that?
奥托 我要生了
Otto, I think it's time.
我要生了
I think it's time.
It's time.
我是心脏科医生 我帮妳叫妇产科医生
Oh, uh, I'm a cardiologist. I'll page OB for you.
想想办法 我要生了
Do something. It's time!
"是个男孩"
准备好了吗
All right, ready?
大家来拍大合照
All right, picture, everybody!
拍照啰
Picture, picture, picture.
好了吗 大家说"马可"
All right. Ready? Everybody say, "Marco."
一 二 三
One, two, three.
马可
Marco!
奥托
Otto!
奥托 进来啊
-Hola. Hi! -Hey, Otto. Come in.
大伙儿 这是我们的朋友奥托
Everyone, this is our friend Otto.
嗨 奥托
Hi, Otto!
嘿 奥托
Hey, Otto.
抱歉 这是关于门口停的车吗
Sorry, is this about the cars that are in front?
不是 我带了东西给妳
No, I brought you something.
奥托
Otto.
我重新上过漆
I gave it a fresh coat of paint.
我好喜欢喔
I love it.
这是给宝宝的
-It's for the baby. -Yes.
谢谢你 帮我抱一下
Thank you. Okay, hold him one second, please.
-为什么  -我去叫汤米来看
-Why? -To show Tommy.
抱住他 他要哭了
Hold him. Oh, he's gonna cry.
我马上回来 好喔
I'll be right back, bebé. Okay.
汤米
Tomaso?
哈啰 好了
Hello. There we are.
该让他再咬奶嘴吗
-Uh, should I put this thing back in him?
来吧
There.
很好
Oh. Yeah.
好了
Okay.
我是奥托阿公
Yo soy Abuelo Otto.
好吗
Okay?
让我把你放在婴儿床上面
Uh, well, let me show you how this works.
你什么都不必做
You don't have to do anything.
轻点
Easy.
你的小脑袋瓜…
Your little head...
现在只要…
Now, you just go...
这样就行
like so.
"索妮娅"
这是艾比和露娜
Sonya, this is Abbie and Luna.
她们有东西给妳
They have something for you.
-嗨 索妮娅
-Hi, Sonya.
那是刚出生的马可
-That's, uh, brand-new little Marco there.
还有我跟妳提过的玛丽索和汤米
And Marisol, Tommy. I told you about them.
说"哈啰 索妮娅"
Say, "Hola. Hola, Sonya."
她很爱粉红色的花
She loved pink flowers, girls.
妳们真会挑
You chose well.
我也喜欢粉红色
I like pink too.
看到吗
You see that?
-好了吗  -好了
-Ready? -Yes.
好吧
Okay.
不
No.
不不不
No, no, no.
拜托 奥托
Come on, Otto.
"玛丽索启"
马尔坎 检查机油
All right, Malcolm, check that oil. Check it.
看看怎么样
And let's see, what does it say?
不错 对吧
Looks good, right?
你说了算
-If you say so. -Okay.
-好了 -就这样
That's it. Okay, now...
好了 这是使用手册
Here's your manual.
这是行照
Here's your papers.
还有车钥匙
And the key.
这是你的车了
It's your car.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
没有
Nope.
什么
What?
奥托
Otto!
谢谢你 谢谢你
Thank you. Oh, thank you.
-天啊 -你不必开福斯了
-Oh, my gosh. -Saved you from a Volkswagen.
我有车子了
I have a car! I have a car!
-这是你的车 -开什么玩笑
-This is your car! -Are you kidding me?
奥托 你买了货卡
Otto? You got your truck!
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
想去兜风吗
Wanna go for a ride?
-去兜风  -很赞的货卡喔
-Let's go for a ride? -That's a nice truck, Otto.
小心点
Be careful.
我喜欢你的车子
I like your car, Otto.
是吗 开起来更棒
Yeah? Wait till you see how it rides.
超大的
It's enormous.
这就像摔角手奥托的怪兽卡车
This is like Otto's luchador monster truck.
你有漫画吗
Yeah. Do you have any comics?
能去吃瑞典闪电泡芙吗
Can we get Swedish éclairs?
这才算过生活
This is livin'.
♪ Every morning I get up ♪
♪ Look out my window I get up ♪
噢 好吧
Oh, okay.
♪ See the sunshine beating down ♪
♪ Every morning comes around ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Every morning... ♪
好了 谁要吃早餐
Okay, who's ready for breakfast?
来啰
Okay. Here we go.
好吗
Okay?
-马可都三岁了 -你长得好快
-I can't believe Marco's 3 already. -You're such a big boy.
我去开门
-I'll get it, honey.
嘿 老婆
Hey, honey?
奥托没有铲雪
Otto hasn't shovelled his walk.
看好妳弟弟
Watch your brother.
去拿钥匙
Get the keys.
奥托
Otto?
Otto.
奥托
玛丽索
Marisol.
Marisol,
如果妳在读这封信 别担心
if you're reading this, don't worry.
我没做任何蠢事
I haven't done anything stupid.
结果心太大了
It turns out having a big heart
并没有听起来的那么好
isn't as nice as it sounds.
医生警告说这最后会害死我
The doctors warned me it would get me in the end,
我只是事先做好准备而已
so I planned ahead, that's all.
猫咪每天吃鲔鱼两次
The cat eats tuna twice a day
而且喜欢躲起来大小便
and likes to do his business in private.
请尊重那一点
Please respect that.
我想办一场葬礼
I would like a funeral.
我们在此缅怀你…
We remember before you this day...
但不要太夸张
But nothing overblown.
…我们的弟兄奥托
...our brother Otto.
只是一场纪念会
Just a remembrance of some sort...
为了觉得我有所贡献的人
for those people who thought I pulled my weight.
缅怀一名本地英雄 以及本节目的好朋友
A local hero and good friend of the show is being remembered today.
奥托安德森
Otto Anderson.
吉米 你想说几句话纪念奥托吗
Jimmy, would you like to say a few words about Otto?
好的
Yeah. Otto, we love you.
奥托 我们爱你 为了纪念你
In your honour, Malcolm and I are doing
我和马尔坎每天替你巡逻社区 午休时间和工作日
all of your rounds without fail around lunch and on weekdays.
你在我们心中占有一席之地
You loom large.
"安息 阿公"
我的律师会让妳用我的银行帐户
My lawyer will give you access to my bank accounts.
我从不乱花钱买东西
I never wasted money on crap,
妳会有足够的钱让小孩念完书
so you'll have enough to get the children through school.
妳是怎么做到的
How'd you do that?
"索妮娅安德森青少年危机基金"
剩下的钱随便妳花
And do what you like with the rest.
乖狗狗
Oh, good boy.
那是狗狗蛋糕吗
Is that a doggie cake?
我的小乖
My little monkey-poo.
敬奥托
To Otto.
房子和里面的一切都是妳的
The house, and everything in it, is yours,
只要妳保证不把它卖给那些建商混蛋
so long as you promise never to sell it to those real estate bastards.
拜托妳 玛丽索…
And for God's sakes, Marisol...
汤米
Tommy.
…别让汤米开那台雪佛兰
...don't let Tommy drive the Chevy.
来吧
Come on.
别让任何人开
Or anyone else, for that matter.
我只信任妳
I'm trusting it with you alone.
因为妳不是白痴
Because you are not an idiot.
奥托阿公
Abuelo Otto.
♪ Sun through the shadows ♪
♪ Light through the door ♪
♪ Voice like an echo ♪
♪ I can't hear anymore ♪
♪ So I follow your steps ♪
♪ While the love that you left ♪
♪ Is burned in my heart ♪
♪ With dreams in my mind ♪
♪ Of the next time that I ♪
♪ Have you in my arms ♪
♪ 'Cause I will tell you the whole truth ♪
♪ That there's no colour ♪
♪ In the world without you ♪
若您或身边的人有遇到心理困扰
♪ And I finally see ♪
♪ How your love is the best of me ♪
美国以外的国家
请到
www.findahelpline.com
关爱自己 也多关心身边的人
♪ Yeah, there's so much I want you to know ♪
♪ Guess I'll wait till you're home ♪
♪ Mm-mm-mm-mm ♪
♪ The way that you smile ♪
♪ When you think you're alone ♪
♪ The best gift of this life ♪
♪ Is to see you up close ♪
♪ Now and again ♪
♪ In the palm of my hand ♪
♪ I feel your touch ♪
♪ So I write it all down ♪
♪ In these moments I've found ♪
♪ 'Til I see you, my love ♪
♪ And I will tell you the whole truth ♪
♪ That there's no colour ♪
♪ In the world without you ♪
♪ And I finally see ♪
♪ How your love is the best of me ♪
♪ Yeah, there's so much I want you to know ♪
♪ Guess I'll wait 'til you're home ♪
♪ Mm-mm-mm-mm. ♪